pedr.co.uk 2018-05-03

# PEDR Privacy Policy

###  Privacy Policy

Our commitment to your privacy

#### 1\. WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT

The Royal Institute of British Architects (”We” or “RIBA”) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. 

This policy (together with our terms of use and any other documents referred to on it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. By visiting www.pedr.co.uk you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy. 

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act), the data controller is RIBA of 66 Portland Place, London, W1B 1AD. 

We store all the information you enter when you register to use this site. If you subscribe to the PEDR all information relating to your professional experience records is also stored. We also record the date you subscribed, the last time you logged in and, if you pay for PEDR, the method of payment. We do not store any credit or debit card details. We process this personal data for the purposes of administering your professional experience records and to correspond with you by phone, email or otherwise. 

We also keep records relating to site access, e.g. pages visited, time of visits, but this information is not related to individuals. 

#### 2\. HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

If you agreed at the time of registration we may contact you from time to time with details of products, surveys and special offers. You can opt out from this at any time by visiting your account or unsubscribing from email communications. 

We will use this information to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us and in particular to process your payment details, fulfil your order and provide support services. RIBA will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

#### 3\. WILL THE INFORMATION BE DISCLOSED TO OTHER PARTIES?

Your registration details may be passed on to Professional Studies Advisors, if you are completing the PEDR Recording records. 

If anybody else wants to see your PEDR Record information, for example as part of a research project, you will be asked before it is disclosed. 

When you register to use the PEDR website, RIBA will store your e-mail address along with any other information you may provide. When you use the services on the website, we may need to collect further information about you. This information may include, but is not limited to, details such as your name and address 

We never disclose your information to any third parties outside of the RIBA Group of companies unless specifically requested to so by you. The information may also be used to notify you of products and services from RIBA which may be of interest to you, unless you advise RIBA of your wish not to receive such information. 

By disclosing your personal information to RIBA, you agree to collection, storage and processing of your personal information in the manner set out here. 

#### 4\. COOKIES

The site uses a type of cookie called a session variable, to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our site. These are never written on the hard drive and they do not collect any information from the user's computer. These are automatically deleted from the user's computer when the browser is closed. For more information see [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/)

If you use the spell checker then the words you add to your dictionary are stored in a cookie on your hard drive. 

#### 5\. YOUR RIGHTS

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at RIBA, 66 Portland Place, London W1B 1AD or email education@riba.org
